Mohammed Ibrahim Abdelkader

Contact No. : +971 50 2039240/+971 56 1412442

E- mail Address : midofgb@yahoo.com



Objective

To seek a challenging position within a dynamic team of a progressive, reputed organization in order to utilize my Sales/Marketing customer services experience to achieve results and attain professional growth, while embracing new methodologies to remain competitive in the market.

Personal & Professional Profile

- 16 years of professional experience of Sales & Marketing/Customer Service in Banking industry.
- Graduated in the Bachelor of Science and Education, mathematics Department.
- Having comprehensive problem-solving abilities
- Ability to deal with people diplomatically with effective communication skills.
- Honest, hardworking, result-oriented and resourceful
- Willingness to learn with emphasis on details.
- Punctual, aggressive, confident & dynamic
- A Self-initiator, proactive with sound judgment, planning skills for business development.
- Dealing effectively with multicultural environment

Professional Experience

Dubai Health Authority, Dubai, UAE

Jan 2021 - till date

Call Centre Representative

- Dealing with calls in a highly professional manner.
- How to act as the first point of telephone contact for a customer.
- Handling complaints in a diplomatic way.
- Accurately updating customer records with information.
- Responding to customers who have special communication needs, such as language difficulties or disabilities.
- Answering any queries quickly and efficiently.
- Quickly understanding a caller's point of view and to empathise with them.
- Able to respond and adapt to the needs of all customers.

- Fully aware of all laws & regulations regarding data protection.
- Quickly processing information.

Emirates Islamic Bank, Dubai, UAE

Feb 2013 -Oct 2019

Personal Banking Advisor

- Listens to and follows through on customer inquiries, requests, complaints.
- Keeps customer up- to date about progress.
- Provide product and service information.
- Makes self-available to deal with customer's problems or needs.
- Advice and relevant products and services to customers to increase their awareness and promote their usage.
- Create and exploit opportunities to promote and sell a portfolio of products and services that
 meets the needs of existing and prospective customers to achieve the assigned sales
 objectives/standards.
- Make appropriate customer referrals to other units to facilitate retention and continued relationship.
- Address customer problems and complaints to achieve satisfactory resolutions, referring issues beyond his role limit to appropriate points of reference.
- Approve or recommend, to set levels, customer applications for products/ services to meet their needs.
- Apply, and comply with, relevant processes, procedures, and controls to meet the unit's needs while providing efficient service to customer.
- Maintain strict control of confidential documents secured negotiable items to prevent loss or misuse.

Dubai Bank, Sharjah, UAE

Nov 2008-Jan 2013

Call centre Officer.

- Help increase customer base through friendly, attentive service.
- Cross sell numerous bank products to customers and open savings accounts.
- Liaise between customers and sales.
- Anticipate customer's needs and empathise with diverse customers.
- Quickly identify and resolve customer's problems to increase customer retention.
- Listen and respond to customers' requests and follow-up to ensure complete satisfaction and loyalty.
- Communicate benefits of products and promotions to new and returning customers.
- Educate customers on different procedures and services.

Relationship Officer

- Responsible for Sales & Marketing of the bank's products. (Islamic Personal Finance)
- To contribute to development of sound revenue, cost budgets and marketing plans through maximization of every business opportunity and effective account management
- Negotiate, conclude, and manage sales deals with corporate and trade accounts.
- Impress each customer with fast, friendly, and providing prompt, personalized service to regular customers.
- Attending customers of high profile and assisting them to choose the right product.
- Analyse customer needs and provide recommendations that address those requirements.
- Provide management with timely sales information (sales report, prospect list etc.)
- Have successfully achieved and exceeded targets set by effective product demonstration, assuring
 the customers, consumers proper after sales service and maintain lasting relationship with the

First Gulf Bank, Ajman, UAE

June 2005-to July 2007

Senior Sales cum customer Service Representative.

- Responsible for customer services & sales of the bank's products. (Personal loan)
- To contribute to development of sound revenue, cost budgets and marketing plans through maximization of every business opportunity and effective account management
- Negotiate, conclude and manage sales deals with corporate and trade accounts.
- Impress each customer with fast, friendly and providing prompt, personalized service to regular customers.
- Attending customers of high profile and assisting them to choose the right product.
- Analyse customer needs and provide recommendations that address those requirements.
- Provide constructive feedback on customers' complaints, requests and service development.
- Provide management with timely sales information (sales report, prospect list etc.)
- Have successfully achieved targets set by effective product demonstration, assuring the customers, consumers proper after sales service and maintain lasting relationship with them.
- Build customer base and manage intention of enhancement of bank's sales & service in the area.

Al Maghrabi Services, Sharjah, UAE Sales & Marketing

November 2003 to June 2005

Job Profile:

- Responsible for marketing the company's projects, gathering market information.
- Responsible for marketing and promoting manpower supply & cleaning services to Customers through Sales Presentation, account relationship building sales forecasting and related duties.
- Effectively negotiate and close high—priced sales
- Identified market opportunities and increased sales revenue.

Educational Qualification

Bachelor of Science and education, mathematics Department from Mansoura University, Egypt –
 2000.

Computer Skills

- Well versed with Windows
- Microsoft Office Package MS Word, MS Excel,

• Proficiency in E-mail and Internet applications.

Training Attended

- General Banking (FIRST GULF BANK)
- E-Induction & E-Shari'ah (HR Intranet)
- Principles of Islamic Banking (EIBFS)
- Up your Service (In-House Training)

Personal Details

D.O.B: 12/01/1978. Nationality: Egyptian
 Marital status: Married. Visa: Employment Visa

3. **Driving License:** Holding a valid U.A.E driving license and own a car.

4. Languages known Arabic, English.

References

• Will be readily furnished upon request.

* * * * *